#### Kamran Amini

+31 (0) 611060215

Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com

Skype: kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp March 31, 2018 Page 1

#### IN SUMMARY

As a highly motivated and expert software architect, I have spent more than 10 valuable years dealing with the analysis, design, development, and building large-scale, national, governmental and international enterprise systems and my skills are not limited to a specific development platform. My architectural solutions include a variety of technologies, patterns, and concepts based on C/C++, Java, Python, etc without any pre-biased point of view. As an architect for governmental and international enterprise software, I've always faced strict and risky conditions in which security, performance, data consistency, data correctness, distribution of resources, fault tolerance, high availability, authentication, and authorization, etc have always been important factors. Recently, because of my old academic interest in Data Science and Machine Learning, I have accepted to be a Deep Learning research developer and give possible consultant for algorithm and software development. I am also highly passionate about Astronomy and Cosmology which made me pursue it as an official university degree. Recently, blockchain and cryptocurrencies have been the target of my self-studies and because of my former experience with PKI, the future use and possible alternatives for blockchain are interesting topics to me.

## EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCES

#### TomTom

Netherlands, Amsterdam September 2017 - Present

#### Expert Software Engineer (As a contractor from Ajilon IT)

- Development Environment: Ubuntu, Perforce, git, Test Driven Development (GTest), Scrum (Jira, Fisheye, Confluence), C++ and C++ 11, Jenkins
- As Expert Software Engineer: Being part of the Search team, I mainly work on the components that are written using C++ 11 and integrated using Bash/Python and Perl scripts.

# Ajilon IT

Netherlands, Amsterdam September 2017 - Present

# Senior Software Engineer/Architect

 Working as Senior Software Engineer and Senior Software Architect consultant. My first cooperation experience with Ajilon IT has been TomTom.

# Jeppesen, a Boeing company

Sweden, Gothenburg

February 2017 - August 2017

# Expert C++/Python Engineer (As a contractor from Telescope Services AB)

- Development Environment: Redhat based Linux distribution, Mercurial, Test Driven Development, Scrum, C++, Python, Jenkins, C#.NET for UI development
- As Senior C++/Python Engineer: Mainly working on Manpower Planning product, back-end and core libraries which they are C++ and Python. Sometimes some modifications are needed on the UI side which is in C#.NET.

## Telescope Services AB

Sweden, Lund

January 2017 - August 2017

## Senior Software Engineer/Architect

 Working as Senior Software Engineer and Senior Software Architect consultant. My first cooperation experience with Telescope has been Jeppesen. Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com

Skype: kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp March 31, 2018 Page 2

#### Sahab Pardaz Co.

Iran, Tehran

July 2016 - February 2017

## Deep Learning Research Developer, Enterprise Software Architect, Project Manager

- Development Environment: Debian based Linux distributions, Git, Redmine Issue Tracker, Test Driven Development, Free IDE, Agile based methodology, gcc, g++ and OpenJDK 8 compilers, C++11 for back-end services, etc.
- As a Deep Learning Research Developer: Cooperation with researchers and other developers on design of deep models in order to overcome a specific problem; Development of designed Machine Learning and Deep models in various programming languages like C, C++ and Python; Gathering, preparation and refining train data and feeding to the model; Evaluation and updating model according to new train data; Measurement of different factors of a learning model like error rate in order to study model behavior; Working with various frameworks like TensorFlow, Torch, Theano, OpenCV, etc; Doing GPU and CPU computation using CUDA, Theano, TensorFlow, etc
- As an Enterprise Software Architect: Studying various aspects of a software in order to detect and design core interfaces, business boundaries, contracts and constraints in each subsystem; Use of state-of-the-art architectural patterns and technologies in order to have a modern and working software, Meeting with other architects in order to share knowledge and understandings about a problem and give solutions; Guiding senior developers and managers in order to have a clean and planned implementation
- As a Project Manager: Arranging different teams for a project like architects, developers, analysts, designers, testers, etc; Conducting sessions with stack holders and product managers in order to have a better understandings about the software; Preparing time schedules for supervisors; Assigning tasks to different teams; Monitoring and organizing activities from various teams to keep the progress up and running

## Adro Co.

Iran, Tehran

June 2016 - February 2017

#### Senior Software Architect, Senior C++ Engineer

- Projects: Real Time Bidding (RTB) Engine serving millions of requests from Supply Side Platforms (SSP) and other RTB Engines.
- Development Environment: Ubuntu Server, g++, gdb, valgrind memory profiler, CMake, git, TFS, etc.
- As a Senior Software Architect: Providing design and architecture of the RTB engine serving more than 200 million requests (advertisement impressions) per day; Introducing scalability and HA featuress to an existing RTB engine; Conducting architectural sessions in order to provide a fine solution to sudden issues; Guidance through the selection of development and build tools; Providing safe solutions to transactional and financial operations.
- Technologies: Asynchronous IO and IO event driven development using libev and libuv libraries; HAProxy; Linux Virtual Server (LVS); Real Time Kernel; OpenRTB Specification; Multithreading; Redis; Deep Packet Injection; Nginx load balancing; Gatling; libeio; libcares for Asynchronous DNS Resolving; systemd and journald services; libnuma for Non-Uniform Memory Access; TCMalloc for thread wise buffer caching

## Noavaran Tejarat Gostar Naeem Co.

Iran, Tehran

April 2015 - October 2016

#### Chief Technical Officer, Senior Software Architect, Senior C/C++ Developer

- Development Environment: Ubuntu Desktop; Ubuntu Server; git; Jenkins; Redmine Issue Tracker; Test Driven Development; Free IDE; Agile based methodology; gcc, g++ and OpenJDK 7 compilers; C++11 for back-end services; Python 2 and 3; etc.
- As a Chief Technical Officer: Managing and coaching more than 15 software and hardware developers organized in 6 different teams; Strategic decision making for company's technical future; Cooperation with and coaching research teams operating in Image Processing, Machine Learning, NLP, Security, Hardware, Cryptography, Mathematics fields; Supervising all data structures and algorithms proposed by research team and coaching developers and architects through implementation phase; Conducting sessions with academic people and using the top most national knowledge to supply the research teams

+31 (0) 611060215

Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com

Skype: kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp March 31, 2018 Page 3

- As a Senior Software Architect: Service Oriented Architecture; Micro Service Architecture; C/C++ based Architecture; Java SE/EE based Architecture; Distributed Architecture; Clouding strategies like SaaS, IaaS, PaaS; High performance message queues; Micro-batching and stream processing; Durable queues; Supervising testers and designed test scenarios; etc
- Technologies: PKI; Design of CA Infrastructure; ICAO CSCA and DS Arhcitecture; NFC tags and chips; NFC readers and writers; ICAO Documents 9303; Biometric algorithms and engines; Architecting ABIS; Distributed processing and data storage like Hadoop, XtreemFS, Gluster, etc; Architecting Network Analysis engines; Huge data structures; In memory data structures; Query languages using Yacc and Lex; Apache Hadoop Family; Apache Cassandra; Redis; Apache ZooKeeper; MemCached; Bloom Filters; Apache Kafka; Apache Storm; Apache Spark; Apache Ignite; Relational PostgreSQL; Object Oriented PostgreSQL; PL/PgSQL; Hottentot RPC Framework; PKCS12; PKCS11 API; PKCS10; PKCS7; etc
- Hardware: Security Tokens and Cryptographic Chips; NFC reader and writer devcies; Embedded Programming; Raspberry Pi 2; Arduino Boards; ARM MCUs; etc
- Projects: Kawthar Geographically Distributed ePassport Issuance System; NETWE Network Analysis Engine; Distributed Crawler Engine; Consular Portal for Iran's Ministry of Foreign Affairs; ABIS Engine; Biometric Data Enrolment Applications; Query language for NETWE using Yacc/Lex

### Sahab Pardaz Co.

Iran, Tehran

February 2015 - June 2015

#### Distributed Systems Architect, Senior Java SE/EE Engineer, C++ Engineer

- Development Environment: Ubuntu Desktop; Ubuntu Server; git and Mercurial; Jenkins; Gerrit; Redmine Issue Tracker; Test Driven Development; Free IDE; Scrum methodology; gcc, g++ and OpenJDK 7 compilers; etc.
- As a Software Architect: Focusing on scalable systems with high throughputs and balancing the load among many nodes; Participation in architecting sessions; Supervising C/C++ and Java developers; Designing tests and test scenarios; Maven-based versioning system for writing embedded stubs for facilitate test scenarios
- Technologies: Apache Hadoop Family; Bloom Filters; Apache ZooKeeper; Apache Cassandra; Redis; MemCached; Apache Kafka; Apache Storm; Apache Spark; Apache Ignite; RPC solutions like GRPC (Google RPC); ZeroIce; etc

### Mojtama E Fanni Tehran (Tehran Technical Complex)

Iran, Tehran

March 2013 - June 2015

# Director of Programming Department, C++/Java SE/EE Instructor, Senior Java EE Engineer/Architect

- Development environment: Ubuntu Server, Git, Free IDE, Agile based methodology, gcc, g++ and OpenJDK 6 compilers, etc.
- As a director of department: Managing and supervising classes, Coaching instructors, Designing courses and their syllabus, etc
- As an architect/developer: Developing a service oriented educational system called EduSys, Developing automation and financial systems
- Technologies: Java based development, Web tier using Spring MVC and Spring Security frameworks, PostgreSQL database

# **Sharif CERT Center**

Iran, Tehran

December 2011 - June 2013

Java SE/EE Engineer

### C/C++ Engineer/Architect

- Development environment: Ubuntu Desktop, Ubuntu Server, SVN, Git, Eclipse IDE, Agile based methodology, gcc, g++ and OpenJDK 6 compilers, Test Driven Development, etc.
- As an developer/architect: Research and develop on Network Security concerns (L2 and L3), Working with algorithms and data structures which they are involved in security related topics, Malware analysis, Traffic analysis, Attack analysis
- Technologies: C/C++, Java 6, PostgreSQL, MySQL, JNetPcap, tcpdump, tcpreplay, etc

#### Kamran Amini

+31 (0) 611060215

Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com

Skype: kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp March 31, 2018 Page 4

- 2012 May, Member of Technical Team, CTF Competitions, Iran's Second National Hacking Contest, Sharif University of Technology. Designer and Auditor for Java Secure Coding Question
- 2013 Feb, Member of Technical Team, CTF Competitions, Iran's Second National Hacking Contest, Sharif University of Technology. Designer and Auditor for C++ Secure Coding Question

#### FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Persian(Native), English(Fluent), French(Professional), Dutch(Intermediate)

#### **EDUCATION**

2017 - Present
 The Open University
 Bachelor of Science in Physics (Astronomy and Planetary Science)

2004 - 2008
 University of Isfahan
 Isfahan, Iran
 Bachelor of Software Engineering

#### SCIENTIFIC AND PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Computer Science: Data Structures, Algorithm Design, Automata Theory, Turing Machine
  and Computation Theory, Linear and Abstract Algebra, Information Theory, Cryptography, Quantum Cryptography and Key Distribution, Quantum Computation, Public Key
  Infrastructure, Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Relational Databases, Graph
  Databases, Key-Value Databases, File Systems, Operating Systems, Kernel Architecture,
  Logical Circuits, Digital Circuits, Analogue Circuits, etc
- Data Science: Reinforcement Learning, Classification and Clustering techniques, Deep Learning, Neural Networks, CNNs, RNNs, Training Models, Learning Theory, etc
- Programming Languages: C, Embedded C (ARM, AVR), C++, Java, Python
- Databases: PostgreSQL (Relational and OO), Oracle RDBMS, MySQL, MongoDB, Apache Cassandra, Neo4j, Redis, etc
- Operating Systems: Linux Distros (Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS), FreeBSD
- Source Version Controls: Git, SVN, Mercurial
- Software Engineering and Project Management: MVP, Agile methodologies (Scrum), RUP, etc.
- Frameworks: C++ (STL, Boost), Java (Spring Family, Hibernate, Hadoop Family, Mockito, JUnit, etc)

# INTERESTED IN

- Mathematics: Linear and Abstract Algebra, Probability Theory, Information Theory
- Philosophy: Western Philosophy, Sociology, Economics, Politics and Humanities
- Physics: Quantum Physics, Quantum Mechanics, Particle Physics, Relativity, Theory of Everything, Photonics
- Cryptography: Information Security, Network Security, Security Algorithms, Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Key Distribution, Quantum Cryptography
- Telecommunications: Modulation, Multiplexing, Codes, Telecommunication circuits, Photonics and optical fibers, IEEE 802.3 Protocols, Information Theory, Coding Theory, Computer Networks, etc
- Music and Musicology: Classic, Extreme Metal, Alternative Metal, Progressive Metal, Alternative Rock, etc